Guide to the James O. Brown Associates Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
James O. Brown Associates Records
1927-1992.
James O. Brown Associates.
231 linear ft. (ca. 210,000 items in 456 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079748
History
Literary agency in New York City. Organized in 1949 as the successor firm to George T. Bye & Company, James Oliver Brown later absorbed the agencies of Maxim Lieber (1951), John Cushman Associates (1978), and others. James Brown Associates merged with Curtis Brown, Ltd. in 1981.
Scope and Content
The files of the literary agency include correspondence with authors, publishers, and other agents and deal with editing and publishing, serial rights, reprints, dramatic rights, translations and foreign rights, promotion, copyright registration, contracts, royalty statements, tax statements, and other financial materials, and the personal affairs of many clients. Among the cataloged correspondents are: Louis S. Auchincloss, Erskine Caldwell, Herbert Gold, Alberto Moravia, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Rebecca West.
1985 ADDITION: 90 personal letters relating to Brown's illness & retirement have been added.
1987 ADDITION: James Oliver Brown donated selected volumes from his library, including 92 books inscribed to him by the authors, his clients. A shelflist of these uncataloged books is available. Other similarly inscribed books, mostly by Louis Auchincloss, have been cataloged & added to the Rare Book Collection.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged (Boxes C1-C48); remainder arranged: Authors, A-Z - Boxes 1-394; Agents, publishers, & subjects - Boxes 395-413; J.O. Brown, personal - Box 414; Contracts - Boxes 415-420; Financial records - Boxes 421-446.
Subjects
Curtis Brown, Ltd.; George T. Bye & Company.; John Cushman Associates.; Auchincloss, Louis.; Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945.; Brown, James Oliver, 1909-; Buck, Frank, 1884-1950.; Burgess, Gelett, 1866-1951.; Bye, George T.; Caldwell, Erskine, 1903-1987.; Carr, John Dickson, 1906-1977.; Coleman, Lonnie, 1920-; Costain, Thomas Bertram, 1885-; Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir, 1859-1930.; Durant, Will, 1885-1981.; Ferber, Edna, 1887-1968.; Freeling, Nicolas.; Gilbert, Michael Francis, 1912-2006.; Gold, Herbert, 1924-; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940.; Hurst, Fannie, 1889-1968.; Lieber, Maxim.; Liebling, A. J. (Abbott Joseph), 1904-1963.; Lockridge, Richard, 1898-1982.; Malleson, Lucy Beatrice, 1899-1973.; Mitford, Jessica, 1917-1996.; Moravia, Alberto, 1907-1990.; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957.; Nash, Ogden, 1902-1971.; Parrott, Ursula, 1899-1957.; Powys, John Cowper, 1872-1963.; Powys, Llewelyn, 1874-1955.; Purdy, James.; Renault, Mary.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Sothern, E. H. (Edward Hugh), 1859-1933.; Stafford, Jean, 1915-1979.; Swados, Harvey.; Terhune, Albert Payson, 1877-1947.; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983.; Wilson, Angus.; Wilson, Sloan, 1920-2003.; Woollcott, Alexander, 1887-1943.; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959.; American literature--20th century.; English literature--20th century.; Authors, American--20th century--Correspondence.; Authors, English--20th century--Correspondence.; Authors and publishers--United States--20th century.; Books--Translations.; Copyright.; Literature publishing.; Novelists, American--20th century--Correspondence.; Novelists, English--20th century--Correspondence.; Publishers and publishing.; Translations.; Account books.; Bank statements.; Bankruptcy proceedings.; Bills.; Card files.; Check stubs.; Contracts.; Financial records.; Lists.; Manuscripts (literary).; Memoranda.; Photographs.; Tax returns.; Literary agents.; Saturday evening post.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 1-446, and volumes from the James Oliver Brown library. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Lonnie Coleman materials (cataloged manuscripts & Boxes 77-79) may not be used without the written permission of Curtis Brown Ltd., 10 Astor Place, NY NY 10003.
Acquisition
1971 M-1971 Records Brown, James Oliver Gift
10/--/1991 M-10-91 H. Gold letter Brown, J.O. Gift
12/--/1991 M-91-12 2 letters from Herbert Gold Brown, J.O. Gift
06/01/1992 M-92-06-01 5 letters Brown, James Oliver Gift
Alternate Formats
John Dickson Carr letters are on microfilm.
Albert Payson Terhune letters are on microfilm.
Laura Wilder letters from Box 380 are on microfilm.
Rose Wilder letters from Boxes 223 & 224 are on microfilm.
Gift of James Oliver Brown, 1971-1981, 1984, 1986-1992.
Finding aid in repository and online.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce (Box C1)
  - Ade, George (Box C1)
  - Anderson, Dame Judith (Box C1)
  - Astor, Brooke Russell (Box C1)
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton
    - To 1970 (Box C1)
    - 1971 on (Box C2)
  - Babcock, Edwina Stanton (Box C2)
  - Bairnsfather, Bruce (Box C2)
  - Bairnsfather, Ceal (Mrs. Bruce) (Box C2)
  - Baldwin, James (Box C2)
  - Bártók, Bela (Box C2)
  - Barton, Bruce (Box C2)
  - Baruch, Bernard Marines (Box C2)
  - Beach, Rex Ellingwood (Box C2)
  - Beaton, Sir Cecil Walter Hardy (Box C2)
  - Beebem William (Box C2)
  - Bercovici, Konrad (Box C2)
  - Bernays, Edward L. (Box C2)
  - Biddle, Francis (Box C2)
  - Borglum, Mary Williams Montgomery (Mrs. Gutzon) (Box C2)
  - Bourke-White, M. (Box C2)
  - Bowles, Chester (Box C2)
  - Braden, Spruille (Box C2)
  - Bromfield, Louis (Box C2)
  - Broun, Heywood (Box C2)
  - Buck, Frank (Box C3)
  - Buck, Gene (Box C3)
  - Bunche, Ralph Johnson (Box C4)
  - Burgess, Gelett (Box C4)
  - Burnett, Whit (Box C4)
  - Burt, Struthers (Box C4)
  - Byrnes, James Francis (Box C4)
  - Caldwell, Erskine
    - To 1952 January (Box C4)
    - 1952 February-August (Box C5)
    - 1952 September -1953 April (Box C6)
    - 1953 May -1954 March (Box C7)
    - 1954 April -December (Box C8)
    - 1955 (Box C9)
    - 1956 January -October (Box C10)
    - 1956 November -1957 July (Box C11)
    - 1957 August -1958 February (Box C12)
    - 1958 March-September (Box C13)
    - 1958 October -1959 June (Box C14)
    - 1959 July -1960 May (Box C15)
    - 1960 June -1961 May (Box C16)
    - 1961 June -1985 (Box C17)
  - Cantor, Eddie (Box C18)
  - Cantwell, Robert (Box C18)
  - Carlisle, Kitty (Box C18)
  - Carr, John Dickson (Box C18)
  - Carrel, Alexis (Box C18)
  - Case, Frank (Box C18)
  - Chapin, Charles E. (Box C19)
  - Claire, Ina (Box C19)
  - Clark, Mark Wayne (Box C19)
  - Cobb, Irvin S. (Box C19)
  - Costain, Thomas B. (Box C19)
  - Cowl, Jane (Box C19)
  - Crewes, Laura Hope (Box C19)
  - Darrow, Clarence (Box C19)
  - Darrow, Ruby H. (Mrs Clarence) (Box C19)
  - Darrow, Whitney (Box C19)
  - Davies, Joseph Edward (Box C19)
  - Davis, Elmer (Box C19)
  - Dewey, Thomas Edmund (Box C19)
  - Dimnet, Ernest (Box C19)
  - Dix, Dorothy (Box C19)
  - Dobie, J. Frank (Box C20)
  - Dowling, Eddie (Box C20)
  - Downes, Olin (Box C20)
  - Doyle, Adrian Malcolm Conan (Box C20)
  - Doyle, Denis Percy Stewart Conan (Box C20)
  - Durant, Will (Box C20)
  - Eastman, Max (Box C20)
  - Eaton, Walter Prichard (Box C20)
  - Ely, Joseph Buell (Box C20)
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold (Box C20)
  - Erskine, John (Box C21)
  - Fadiman, Clifton (Box C21)
  - Ferber, Edna (Box C21)
  - Forbes, Joan Rosita Torr (Box C21)
  - Ford, Ford Madox (Box C21)
  - Frankfurter, Felix (Box C21)
  - Franklin, Sidney (Box C21)
  - Freeling, Nicolas (Box C21)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Clara Clemens (Box C21)
  - Gaige, Crosby (Box C21)
  - Garden, Mary (Box C21)
  - Gilbert, Michael Francis (Box C21)
  - Gish, Lillian (Box C21)
  - Gleason, James (Box C21)
  - Gold, Herbert
    - 1952-1958 January (Box C22)
    - 1958 February-1963 (Box C23)
    - 1964-1968 (Box C24)
    - 1969-1972 (Box C25)
    - 1973-1974 (Box C26)
    - 1975-1977 May (Box C27)
    - 1977 June -1981 April (Box C28)
    - 1981 April -1991 (Box C29)
  - Goldberg, Rube (Box C30)
  - Golding, Louis (Box C30)
  - Goldman, Emma (Box C30)
  - Gray, David (Box C30)
  - Gregory, Alyse (Box C30)
  - Grew, Joseph Clark (Box C30)
  - Grey, Zane (Box C30)
  - Gross, Milt (Box C30)
  - Guest, Edgar Albert (Box C30)
  - Halliburton, Richard (Box C30)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, II (Box C30)
  - Harriman, Florence Jaffray Hurst (Mrs. J. Borden) (Box C30)
  - Hellman, George Sidney (Box C30)
  - Hill, Frank Ernest (Box C30)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar (Box C30)
  - Hopkins, Harry Lloyd (Box C30)
  - Hughes, Richard Arthur Warren (Box C30)
  - Hughes, Rupert (Box C30)
  - Hull, Cordell (Box C30)
  - Hurst, Fannie (Box C30)
  - Hutchins, Robert May nard (Box C30)
  - James, Will (Box C30)
  - Johnson, Burges (Box C30)
  - Jolas, Eugene (Box C30)
  - Kennedy, Joseph Patrick (Box C30)
  - Keyes, Frances Parkinson (Box C30)
  - Komroff, Manuel (Box C30)
  - Lanchester, Elsa (Box C30)
  - Lardner, Ring (Box C30)
  - Lawes, Lewis E. (Box C30)
  - Levine, Isaac Don (Box C30)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig (Box C30)
  - Liebling, Abbott Joseph (Box C30)
  - Lin, Yutang (Box C30)
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow (Box C30)
  - Lindbergh, Charles August us (Box C30)
  - Lippmann, Walter (Box C30)
  - Lockridge, Richard (Box C31)
  - Loeb, William (Box C32)
  - Long, Huey Pierce (Box C32)
  - Lord, Russell (Box C32)
  - Low, Will Hicok (Box C32)
  - Lowndes, Marie Adelaide Belloc (Box C32)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe (Box C32)
  - Ludwig, Emil (Box C32)
  - Lynes, Russell (Box C32)
  - McBride, Mary Margaret (Box C32)
  - McWilliams, Carey (Box C32)
  - Malleson, Lucy Beatrice (Box C32)
  - Mann, Erika (Box C32)
  - Mantle, Burns (Box C32)
  - Marie Pavlovna, Grand Duchess of Russia (Box C32)
  - Marquis, Don (Box C32)
  - Marx, Groucho (Box C32)
  - Marx, Harpo (Box C32)
  - Menninger, Karl August us (Box C32)
  - Mesta, Perle Skirvin (Box C32)
  - Meyer, Agnes Ernst (Mrs. Eugene) (Box C32)
  - Mitchell, William "Billy" (Box C32)
  - Moore, Grace (Box C32)
  - Moravia, Alberto (Box C32)
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr. (Box C33)
  - Morley, Christopher (Box C33)
  - Namgyal, Hope Cooke (Box C33)
  - Nash, Ogden (Box C33)
  - Nicholson, Meredith (Box C33)
  - Nielsen, Alice (Box C33)
  - Nizer, Louis (Box C33)
  - O'Brien, Edward Joseph Harrington (Box C33)
  - Ogburn, William. Fielding (Box C33)
  - Onassis, Jacqueline Lee Bouvier Kennedy (Box C33)
  - O'Neill, Rose Cecil (Box C33)
  - Orton, Vrest (Box C33)
  - O'Sheel, Shaemas (Box C33)
  - Parrish, Maxfield (Box C33)
  - Parrott, Ursula Towle (Box C33)
  - Pegler, Westbrook (Box C33)
  - Perelman, Sidney Joseph (Box C33)
  - Perkins, Frances (Box C33)
  - Perkins, Maxwell Evarts (Box C33)
  - Pershing, John Joseph (Box C33)
  - Pitkin, Walter Boughton (Box C33)
  - Plunkett, Sir Horace Curzon (Box C33)
  - Pollock, Channing (Box C33)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne (Box C33)
  - Pourtalés, Guy de (Box C33)
  - Powys, John Cowper (Box C33)
  - Powys, Llewelyn (Box C33)
  - Price, G. Ward (Box C33)
  - Pulitzer, Ralph (Box C33)
  - Purdy, James (Box C33)
  - Renault, Mary (Box C34)
  - Reynolds, Quentin (Box C34)
  - Rice, Elmer L. (Box C34)
  - Rice, Grantland (Box C34)
  - Rodgers, Richard (Box C34)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt (Box C34)
  - Root, Elihu (Box C34)
  - Rose, Billy (Box C34)
  - Rosenman, Samuel Irving (Box C34)
  - Ross, Harold Wallace (Box C34)
  - Runyon, Damon (Box C34)
  - Saarinen, Eliel (Box C35)
  - Salten, Felix (Box C35)
  - Selby, John (Box C35)
  - Sennett, Mack (Box C35)
  - Sevareid, Eric (Box C35)
  - Smith, Alfred Emanuel (Box C35)
  - Snow, Charles Percy, Baron Snow (Box C35)
  - So them, Edward Hugh (Box C35)
  - Sousa, John Philip (Box C35)
  - Stafford, Jean (Box C36)
  - Stallings, Laurence (Box C37)
  - Stark, Lloyd C. (Box C37)
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur (Box C37)
  - Stegner, Wallace (Box C37)
  - Steinberg, Saul (Box C37)
  - Stone, Irving (Box C37)
  - Sullivan, Frank (Box C37)
  - Sutherland, Millicent, Duchess of (Box C37)
  - Swados, Harvey
    - 1953-1959 (Box C37)
    - 1960-1965 (Box C38)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard (Box C38)
  - Tambimuttu, Thurairajah (Box C38)
  - Taylor, Deems (Box C38)
  - Terhune, Albert Payson (Box C38)
  - Thomas, Lowell (Box C38)
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra (Box C38)
  - Tolstoy, Leo, Jr. (Box C38)
  - Tomlinson, Henry Major (Box C38)
  - Towne, Charles Hanson (Box C38)
  - Tracy, Honor (Box C39)
  - Tunney, Gene (Box C39)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box C39)
  - Vidal, Gore (Box C39)
  - Weill, Kurt (Box C39)
  - West, Dame Rebecca
    - 1927-1934 (Box C39)
    - 1935-1946 (Box C40)
  - Weston, Edward (Box C40)
  - White, Elwyn Brooks (Box C40)
  - Wilson, Sir Angus Frank Johnstone (Box C40)
  - Wilson, Sloan (Box C40)
  - Winant, John Gilbert (Box C40)
  - Woollcott, Alexander (Box C40)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box C40)
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton
    - A-G (Box C41)
    - I-end (Box C42)
  - Bercovici, Konrad (Box C42)
  - Buck, Frank & Ferrin Fraser (Box C42)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (Box C42)
  - Cantor, Eddie (Box C42)
  - Carrel, Alexis (Box C42)
  - Coleman, Lonnie
    (PRTS J.O. Brown)
    Lonnie Coleman materials may not be used without the written permission of Curtis Brown Ltd., 10 Astor Place, NY NY 10003.
    - Beulah Land
      - Typed Manuscript, with Corrections (Box C44)
      - Typed Manuscript (Gift, 1978) (Box C45)
      - Galley Proofs (Gift, 1978) (Box C46)
    - Look Away, Beulah Land (Box C47)
      - Typed Manuscript (Gift, 1978) (Box C47)
      - Galley Proofs (Box C48)
    - The Writing of Beulah Land--Typed Manuscript (Gift, 1989) (Box C48)
  - Darrow, Clarence (Box C43)
  - Erskine, John (Box C43)
  - Ford, Ford Madox (Box C43)
  - Gold, Herbert (Box C43)
  - Liebling, Abbott Joseph (Box C43)
  - Moravia, Alberto (Box C43)
  - Parrott, Ursula Towle (Box C43)
  - Powys, Llewelyn (Box C43)
  - Renault, Mary (Box C43)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt (Box C43)
  - Selby, John (Box C43)
  - Stafford, Jean (Box C43)
  - Satllings, Laurence (Box C43)
  - West, Dame Rebecca (Box C43)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box C43)
  - Unidentified manuscripts & scenarios (Box C43)
- Series III: Author File
  - Abbe, John, Patience, Polly, & Richard (Box 1)
  - Abbazia, Michael J. (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Gerald F. (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Stanley & Monica "Lesley Howard" (Box 1)
  - Abeel, William C. (Box 1)
  - Abend, Hallett (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Leon "John Leyden" (Box 1)
  - Abtey, Jacques (Box 1)
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce (Box 1)
  - Adams, Junius (Box 1)
  - Adams, Molly (Box 1)
  - Adams, Nancy Stevenson (Box 1)
  - Adduci, Frank, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Ade, George (Box 1)
  - Adleman, Robert H. (Box 2-3)
  - Aikman, Lounelle Davison & Jefferson Bowman (Box 4)
  - Airth, Rennie (Box 4)
  - Aistrop, J. Bentley (Box 4)
  - Aitken, Jonathan & Michael Beloff (Box 4)
  - Akmakjian, Hiag "Kuro Kawa" (Box 4)
  - Alber, Jouis John (Box 4)
  - Albornoz, Miguel (Box 4)
  - Aldridge, James (Box 4)
  - Alexander, Mary Jean (Box 5)
  - Alexander, Shuford M., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Alexander, Sidney (Box 5)
  - Ali, Tarig (Box 5)
  - Alihan, Milla (Box 5)
  - Alinsky, Saul David (Box 5)
  - Allaby, Michael & Floyd Allen (Box 5)
  - Allbeury, Ted "Richard Butler" (Box 5)
  - Allen, Edgar Fletcher (Box 5)
  - Allen, Lawrence A. (Box 5)
  - Allen, Virginia Paxton (Box 5)
  - Allan, William (Box 5)
  - Alsop, Susan Mary Jay Patten (Box 5)
  - Altman, Dennis (Box 5)
  - Alvarez, Alfred (Box 5)
  - Alvarez, Octaviano (Box 5)
  - Ambrister, Trevor (Box 6)
  - Ambrose, Stephen E. (Box 6)
  - Amery, Julian (Box 6)
  - Amory, Mark Heathcote- (Box 6)
  - Amoury, Daisy (Box 6)
  - Andersen, Fred (Box 6)
  - Anderson, Ian (Box 6)
  - Anderson, John & Stearns Morse (Box 6)
  - Anderson, Robert Gordon (Box 6)
  - Andreski, Stanislav (Box 7)
  - Andrews, Charlton (Box 7)
  - Andrews, Lucilia "Diana Gordon" (Box 7)
  - Andrews, Lyman (Box 7)
  - Angly, J. Edward (Box 7)
  - Angrave, Bruce (Box 7)
  - Ankeny, Nesmith (Box 7)
  - Anthony, Eugene (Box 7)
  - Anthony, Maggy (Box 7)
  - Anthony, Norman (Box 7)
  - Ard, William T. (Box 8-9)
    ("Ken Hamlin", "Ben Kerr", "Mike Moran", "Jonas Ward", "Thomas Wills")
  - Armat, Virginia C. (Box 10)
  - Armstrong, Orland Kay (Box 10)
  - Armstrong, Tilly "Tania Langley" (Box 10)
  - Arneson, D.J. (Box 10)
  - Arnold, Bruce (Box 10)
  - Arnold, G. William (Box 10)
  - Arnott, Kathleen (Box 10)
  - Aryain, Edward E. (Box 10)
  - Ascoli, Max (Box 10)
  - Asher, Don (Box 11-12)
  - Aswell, James (Box 13-14)
  - Atkin, Ronald (Box 15)
  - Atkinson, Alex (Box 15)
  - Atkinson, Anthony Barnes & Joseph Stiglitz (Box 15)
  - Atwell, Ben (Box 15)
  - Auchincloss, Adele Lawrence (Mrs. Louis S.) (Box 15)
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton (Box 16-27)
  - Austen, Roger (Box 28)
  - Austin, Alex (Box 28)
  - Austin, Frederick Britten (Box 28)
  - Axtell, J. William (Box 28)
  - Aykroyd, Wallace Ruddell (Box 28)
  - Babbin, Jacqueline'' (Box 28)
  - Bacal, Jacques (Box 28)
  - Bachelder, Mabel Linda (Box 28)
  - Bachmann, Lawrence P. (Box 28)
  - Baer, Arthur "Bugs" (Box 28)
  - Baer, Fred E. (Box 28)
  - Baer, Howard (Box 28)
  - Bail, Frank W. (Box 28)
  - Bairnsfather, Bruce (Box 28)
  - Baker, Frank (Box 28)
  - Baker, Louise (Box 28)
  - Baker, Richard M., Jr. (Box 28)
  - Balchen, Bernt (Box 29)
  - Balderston, Marion Braley (Box 29)
  - Baldrige, Letitia Katherine (Box 29)
  - Baldwin, Hanson Weightman (Box 29)
  - Baldwin, Joseph Clark (Box 29)
  - Baldwin, Margaret W. (Box 29)
  - Bales, William Alan (Box 29)
  - Ballad, Richard & Wayne Lewis (Box 29)
  - Barber, Richard W. (Box 29)
  - Barbour, Charlotte (Box 29)
  - Barclay, Sheppard (Box 29)
  - Barker, Dudley Raymond (Box 29)
    ("Lionel Black", "Anthony Matthews")
  - Barker, Lester C. (Box 29)
  - Barker, Lillian (Box 29)
  - Barker, Michael J. (Box 29)
  - Barna, Yon (Box 29)
  - Barnes, Howard (Box 29)
  - Barnes, Julius Howland (Box 29)
  - Barnett, Bruce W. (Box 29)
  - Barney, Helen Corse (Box 29)
  - Barnini, Edward (Box 29)
  - Baron, Walter & James B (Box 29)
  - Barr, Donald (Box 29)
  - Barr, Patricia Miriam (Box 29)
  - Barrett, Marvin (Box 30)
  - Barrington, John (Box 30)
  - Barron, Bernard S. (Box 30)
  - Barron, John (Box 30)
  - Barry, Margaret Stuart (Box 30)
  - Barry, Robert (Box 30)
  - Barry-Martin, D.E. (Box 30)
  - Barsantee, Harry (Box 30)
  - Bartlett, B. (Box 30)
  - Bartlett, Jeanne (Box 30)
  - Bartlett, Margaret (Box 30)
  - Bartlett, Robert S. (Box 30)
  - Barton, Pat (Box 30)
  - Basketle, Kurtley (Box 30)
  - Basnett, Fred (Box 30)
  - Bassett, Amy G. (Box 30)
  - Bassler, Robert (Box 30)
  - Batigne, Rene (Box 30)
  - Battersby, Mark E. (Box 30)
  - Batten, R. Peter (Box 30)
  - Baughman, Bruce (Box 30)
  - Bawden, Nina Mary Mabey (Box 30)
  - Bayer, William S., II (Box 30)
  - Beachcroft, Thomas Owen (Box 31)
  - Beahan, Charles (Box 31)
  - Bearden, Romare H. (Box 31)
  - Beaton, Sir Cecil Walter Hardy (Box 31)
  - Beaton, Leonard (Box 31)
  - Beattie, Edward W. (Box 31)
  - Beatty, Jerome (Box 31)
  - Beaty, Betty (Box 31)
    ("Karen Campbell", "Catherine Ross")
  - Beaty, David (Box 31)
  - Beauchamp, Robert Henry (Box 31)
  - Beck, Edward W. (Box 31)
  - Becker, Henry L. (Box 31)
  - Becker, John (Box 31)
  - Beckham, Barry (Box 31)
  - Beckwith, Lillian (Box 31)
    ("Lillian Comber")
  - Bedford, Ethelda (Box 32)
  - Bedford, William (Box 32)
  - Beeding, Francis (Box 32)
    (John Leslie Palmer and Hilary Aidan St. George Saunders)
  - Beer, Thomas (Box 32)
  - Bela, Nicholas (Box 32)
  - Belcher, W.E. (Box 32)
  - Bell, Corydon (Box 32)
  - Bell, Edward Price & Edward Price Bell, Jr. (Box 32)
  - Bell, Josephine (Box 32)
    (Doris Bell Collier Ball)
  - Bellak, Leopold (Box 32)
  - Beloff, Michael (Box 32)
  - Beloff, Nora (Box 32)
  - Benchley, Robert (Box 33)
  - Benedict, Arthur L. (Box 33)
  - Benedictus, David (Box 33)
  - Benefield (Box 33)
  - Benjamin, Edward H. (Box 33)
  - Benford, Timothy B. (Box 33)
  - Bennett, David H. (Box 33)
  - Bennett, James William (Box 33)
  - Bent, Silas (Box 33)
  - Benton, James (Box 33)
  - Bercovici, Konrad (Box 33)
  - Bercovici, Rada (Box 33)
  - Bercovici, Rion (Box 33)
  - Berdin, Richard (Box 33)
  - Berenger, Ralph D. (Box 33)
  - Berger, John (Box 33)
  - Berger, Meyer (Box 33)
  - Bergh, Caroline (Box 33)
  - Bergler, Edmund (Box 33)
  - Bergman, Lee (Box 33)
  - Berkman, Alexander (Box 33)
  - Berkson, Seymour (Box 33)
  - Bernays, Anne (Box 34)
    ("B.K. Pamet")
  - Berry-Hart, Alice H. (Box 34)
  - Berton, Pierre (Box 34)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Box 34)
  - Betjeman, Sir John (Box 34)
  - Beuf, Carlo (Box 34)
  - Beynon, Huw (Box 34)
  - Bickel, Lennard (Box 35)
  - Biemiller, Ruth Cobbett (Box 35)
  - Biery, William (Box 35)
  - Bigsby, Christopher W.E. (Box 35)
  - Billett, Claire Broughton (Box 35)
  - Bischoff, Use (Box 35)
  - Black, Harold (Box 36)
  - Black, Ian Stuart (Box 36)
  - Black, Ruby A. (Box 36)
  - Black, Thomas (Box 36)
  - Blackburn, Alexander L. (Box 36)
  - Blackmore, Jane (Box 36)
  - Blackwood, Caroline (Mrs. Robert Lowell) (Box 36)
  - Bladon, Richard (Box 36)
    ("Anthony Dekker")
  - Blake, Lucile Page (Box 36)
  - Blake, Sally Mirliss ("Sally", "Sara") (Box 36)
  - Blakely, W. Thomas (Box 36)
  - Blanchard, William H. (Box 36)
  - Blashford-Snell, John N. (Box 36)
  - Blau, Raphael David (Box 36)
  - Blauvelt, Hiram (Box 36)
  - Blickhahn, Harry Miller (Box 37)
  - Blixen-Finecke, Baroness Eva von (Box 37)
  - Blocki, Fritz (Box 37)
  - Blond, Anthony (Box 37)
  - Bloom, Ursula (Mrs. Charles Gower Robinson) (Box 37)
    ("Sheila Burns")
  - Bluemle, Andrew (Box 37)
  - Blunt, Wilfred Jasper Walter (Box 37)
  - Boettiger, John & Anna Roosevelt Dall Boettiger (Box 37)
  - Bogoras, Waldemar G. (Vladimir Germanovich Bogoraz) "Tan" (Box 37)
  - Bohn, John Yates (Box 37)
  - Boileau, Pierre & Thomas Narcejac (Box 38)
  - Boishébert-Gasté de Tilly, Comtesse de (Box 38)
  - Bonett, Anne (Box 38)
  - Bonett, John & Emery (John & Felicity Coulson) (Box 38)
  - Bonham-Carter, Victor (Box 38)
  - Bonnell, Dorothy H. (Box 38)
  - Bonnett, Stanley (Box 38)
  - Bonsal, Stephen (Box 38)
  - Booker, Christopher (Box 39)
  - Bookhardt, Fred B., Jr. (Box 39)
  - Booth, Edwina (Box 39)
  - Boram, A (Box 39)
    (, "H. Boron", "Heather Brown")
  - Borgenicht, Miriam (Mirian B. Klein) (Box 39)
  - Boring, James (Box 39)
  - Borsodi, Ralph (Box 39)
  - Bostock, Claude & Carl Kulberg (Box 39)
  - Bourman, Anatole & D. Lyman Green (Box 39)
  - Bovingdon, John (Box 39)
  - Bowen, Roger W. (Box 39)
  - Bowlby, George (Box 39)
  - Bowles, Chester (Box 39)
  - Bowskill, Derek (Box 39)
  - Boyar, Burt & Jane (Box 39)
  - Boyce, Burke (Box 39)
  - Boyd, Martin (Box 39)
  - Boyle, Andrew (Box 39)
  - Boyle, Robert H. (Box 39)
  - Brackenbury, Rosalind (Box 40)
  - Brackett, Charles (Box 40)
  - Bradbury, Malcolm Stanley (Box 40)
  - Braden, Spruille (Box 40)
  - Bradford, Mary Rose Himler (Box 40)
  - Bradna, Fred (Box 40)
  - Brady, J. Michael (Box 40)
  - Brady, Joseph A. (Box 40)
  - Brady, Mariel (Box 40)
  - Bragg, Melvyn (Box 40)
  - Bragg, Pearl (Box 40)
  - Brahms, Caryl & S.J. Simon (Box 40)
  - Braley, Berton (Box 40)
  - Bramble, Forbes (Box 40)
  - Bramwell, Jonathan (Box 40)
  - Brander, Laurence (Box 40)
  - Brandt, Clare (Box 40)
  - Brandt, Mortimer Stirling (Box 40)
  - Brandwynne, Jacqueline & Helen Epstein (Box 40)
  - Brandyce, Harry D. (Box 40)
  - Brasch, Rudolph (Box 40)
  - Brauer, George C., Jr. (Box 40)
  - Bray, Addison (Box 40)
  - Bray, Christopher (Box 40)
  - Breda, Rudolf (Box 41)
  - Breeden, August in W. (Box 41)
  - Bremer, Perry R. (Box 41)
  - Brendon, Piers (Box 41)
  - Brennan, Frederick Hazlitt (Box 41-42)
  - Brennan, John Weston (Box 42)
  - Brentano, Lowell (Box 42)
  - Brewin, George M. (Box 42)
  - Bridgeland, Maurice (Box 42)
  - Brien, Alan (Box 42)
  - Bright, Pamela Mia (Box 42)
  - Brinig, Myron (Box 42)
  - Brink, Carl (Box 42)